Finding Aid for Department of Geological Sciences (University of Michigan of Michigan) Publications, 1933-2003
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Dept. of Geological Sciences (University of Michigan.) publications 1933-20031945-2003
University of Michigan. Dept. of Geological Sciences.
0.8 linear ft.
The University of Michigan. Department of Geological Sciences Publications (.8 linear ft.) include bibliographies, brochures, directories, flyers and newsletters dating from 1933 to the present. These publications primarily document the activities of the department, faculty, staff, students and alumni. In addition, there is information on the summer geology program run by the University of Michigan at Camp Davis in Jackson, Wyoming and Mill Springs, Kentucky.
0370, Bimu, C26, 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The publications are received periodically from the unit (Donor No. 1871 ).
The record group is open without restriction.
For background of this unit, please consult the history found in the University of Michigan. Department of Geological Sciences Records finding aid.
The Department of Geological Sciences Publications are divided into two series: Unit Publications and Topical Publications. The bulk of the publications document the Department of Geological Sciences.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Dept. of Geological Sciences.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Geology.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Geology and Mineralogy.; Geology--Study and teaching (Higher)--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Geology.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Geology and Mineralogy.; Geoalumni news.; Geoscience news.; Contributions to mineralogical sciences from the Department of Geology and Mineralogy from the time of the organization of the department.
Genre/Form:
Bibliographies.; Pamhlets.; Bulletins.; Directories.; Newsletters.
- Unit Publications
  The Unit Publications series contains printed material published specifically by the Department of Geology, Department of Geology and Mineralogy and Department of Geological Sciences. These publications are defined as being widely distributed and may be published at regular intervals. They are arranged by genre of the publication.
  The Unit Publications series includes a bibliography issued in 1964. Contributions to Mineralogical Sciences from the Department of Geology and Mineralogy from the Time of the Organization of the Department includes publications ranging from as early as 1904 to a pre-publication date of 1968. The brochures describe the study of geology at the University of Michigan in addition to information on admission requirements, career opportunities, degree requirements and financial assistance. The directories were issued periodically beginning in 1947 until 1977. The alphabetical portion of the directory includes the alumni's years at the university, degree, present address, position, marriage information, children and their birth dates, other degrees and positions held. The 1947 and 1957 directories mentions war service. The bulk of the publications (.5 linear ft.) are the newsletters. There are four newsletters titles in this series. They include the undated Department of Geology and Mineralogy and the Geoalumni News. The Bentley Library holds issues of Geoalumni News published from 1937 to 1957 and scattered issues from 1962 to 1981. The holdings of The Newsletter date from 1977 to 1982. Covering the period from 1983 to the present Geoscience News continues to document the activities of the department and its faculty, staff, students and alumni.
  - Bibliographies (Box 1)
    - Contributions to Mineralogical Sciences from the Department of Geology and Mineralogy from the Time of the Organization of the Department, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Brochures
    - Geological Sciences, 1982-1989 (Box 1)
    - Geology and Mineralogy, 1973-1975 (Box 1)
    - Graduate Studies in Geological Sciences, undated (Box 1)
    - A Tradition of Leadership, undated (Box 1)
  - Directories
    - Geoalumni Directory
      - 1947 (Box 1)
      - 1957 (Box 1)
      - 1960 (Box 1)
      - 1968 (Box 1)
      - 1977 (Box 1)
  - Flyers, 1980-2006 (Box 1)
  - Invitations
    - Miscellaneous, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters
    - Department of Geology and Mineralogy, undated (Box 1)
    - [Geoalumni News ]
      - 1937-1943, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - 1945-1957, 12 folders (Box 1)
      - 1962 (Box 1)
      - 1967 (Box 1)
      - 1974-1976 (Box 1)
      - 1981 (Box 1)
    - Geoscience News
      - 1983-1990, 5 folders (Box 1)
      - 1994-2006, 6 folders (Box 1)
    - The Newsletter, 1977-1982, 2 folders (Box 1)
- Topical Publications
  The Topical Publications series includes printed materials published to document the Summer Session research opportunities offered by the Department of Geological Sciences. These include mini-bulletins describing summer courses taught at Camp Davis near Jackson Hole, Wyoming in 2002 and 2003. There is also a bulletin discussing the hands-on course work available at Mill Springs, Kentucky in 1933. The newspaper Black Fly is cataloged separately under the call number NB; C186; B627.
  - Summer Session
    - Bulletins
      - Camp Davis, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
      - Geology and Geography Field Courses in Kentucky, 1933